all_q =[
    {
    "numb": 1,
    "question": "What does HTML stand for?",
    "answer": "Hyper Text Markup Language",
    "options": [
      "Hyper Text Preprocessor",
      "Hyper Text Markup Language",
      "Hyper Text Multiple Language",
      "Hyper Tool Multi Language"
    ]
  },
    
{
    "numb": 1,
    "question": "What does CSS stand for?",
    "answer": "Cascading Style Sheet",
    "options": [
      "Common Style Sheet",
      "Colorful Style Sheet",
      "Computer Style Sheet",
      "Cascading Style Sheet"
    ]
  },

{

   "numb": 2,
   "question": "How can we change the background color of an element?",
   "answer": "background-color",
   "options": [
     "bg-col",
     "background-color",
     "color",
     "col",
  ]
},

{
   "numb": 3,
   "question": "How can we change the text color of an element?",
   "answer": "color",
   "options": [
     "color",
     "background-color",
     "txt-color",
     "txt",
  ]
},

{
 "numb": 4,
 "question": "In how many ways can CSS be written in?",
 "answer": "3",
 "options": [
  "1",
  "2",
  "3",
  "4",
 ]
},

 {
  "numb": 5,
  "question": "What type of CSS is generally recommended for designing large web pages?",
  "answer":"External",
  "options": [
  "Inline",
  "External",
  "Internal",
  "None",
 ]
},



{
 "numb": 6,
 "question": "Which HTML tag is used to declare internal CSS?",
 "answer":"<style>",
 "options": [
  "<link>",
  "<script>",
  "<style>",
  "<a>",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 7,
 "question": "How can we select an element with a specific ID in CSS?",
 "answer":"#",
 "options": [
  ".",
  "^",
  "@",
  "#",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 8,
 "question": "How can we write comments in CSS?",
 "answer":"/* */",
 "options": [
  "/* */",
  "//",
  "#",
  "/../",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 9,
 "question": "Can negative values be allowed in padding property?",
 "answer":"No",
 "options": [
  "Yes",
  "No",
  "Depends on Property",
  "None",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 10,
 "question": "The CSS property used to specify the transparency of an element is?",
 "answer":"Opacity",
 "options": [
  "Visibility",
  "Filter",
  "None",
  "Opacity",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 11,
 "question": "Identify the correct extension of the user-defined header file in C++.",
 "answer":".h",
 "options": [
  ".cpp",
  ".hf",
  ".h",
  ".hg",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 12,
 "question": " C++ uses which approach?",
 "answer":"bottom-up",
 "options": [
  "bottom-up",
  "left-right",
  "right-left",
  "top-down",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 13,
 "question": "Which of the following data type is supported in C++ but not in C?",
 "answer":"bool",
 "options": [
  "int",
  "double",
  "float",
  "bool",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 14,
 "question": "Which of the following is â€œaddress of operator ?",
 "answer":"&",
 "options": [
  "^",
  ".",
  "[]",
  "&",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 15,
 "question": "Identify the correct example for a pre-increment operator.",
 "answer":"++n",
 "options": [
  "++n",
  "n++",
  "n+",
  "+n",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 16,
 "question": "Which of the following loops is best when we know the number of iterations?",
 "answer":"for loop",
 "options": [
  "none",
  "while",
  "for loop",
  "do while",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 17,
 "question": "Identify the scope resolution operator",
 "answer":"::",
 "options": [
  "::",
  ":",
  ".",
  ",",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 18,
 "question": "goto can be classified into?",
 "answer":"label",
 "options": [
  "operator",
  "label",
  "variable",
  "function",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 19,
 "question": "Identify the correct definition of * operator in pointer.",
 "answer":"value of ",
 "options": [
  "value of",
  "star",
  "not defined",
  "multiplication",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 20,
 "question": "By which of the following can the if-else statement be replaced?",
 "answer":"conditional operator",
 "options": [
  "conditional operator",
  "logical operator",
  "arithmetic operator",
  "bitwise operator",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 21,
 "question": "How are String represented in memory in C?",
 "answer":"an array of characters",
 "options": [
  "an array of characters",
  "object of some class",
  "linked list of chars",
  "primitive types",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 22,
 "question": "What is the disadvantage of arrays in C?",
 "answer":"Amount of memory to be allowacated should be known beforehand",
 "options": [
  "Amount of memory to be allowacated should be known beforehand",
  "elements of an array can be accessed in constant time",
  "elements are stored in contiguous memory blocks",
  "none",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 23,
 "question": "Which of the following is the proper syntax for declaring macros in C?", 
 "answer":"#define ll long long",
 "options": [
  "#define long ll long",
  "#define ll long",
  "#define ll",
  "#define ll long long",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 24,
 "question": "Which of the following is an exit controlled loop?",
 "answer":"Do-While loop",
 "options": [
  "for loop",
  "while loop",
  "Do-While loop",
  "none",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 25,
 "question": "What is the size of the int data type (in bytes) in C?",
 "answer":"4",
 "options": [
  "1",
  "4",
  "2",
  "8",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 26,
 "question": "How to declare a double-pointer in C?",
 "answer":"int **val",
 "options": [
  "int *val",
  "int **val",
  "int &val",
  "int &&val",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 27,
 "question": "If p is an integer pointer with a value 1000, then what will the value of p + 5 be?",
 "answer":"1020",
 "options": [
  "1022",
  "1080",
  "1040",
  "1020",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 28,
 "question": "Which of the following are not standard header files in C?",
 "answer":"none",
 "options": [
  "stdlib.h",
  "stdio.h",
  "conio.h",
  "none",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 29,
 "question": "In which of the following languages is function overloading not possible?",
 "answer":"c",
 "options": [
  "c",
  "c++",
  "java",
  "python",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 30,
 "question": "Which of the following are correct file opening modes in C?",
 "answer":"all of the above",
 "options": [
  "r",
  "rb",
  "w",
  "all of the above",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 31,
 "question": "How is a code block indicated in Python?",
 "answer":"Indentation",
 "options": [
  "brackets",
  "key",
  "Indentation",
  "Semi-Colon",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 32,
 "question": "Which of the following concepts is not a part of Python?",
 "answer":"Pointers",
 "options": [
  "Pointers",
  "Loops",
  "Dynamic Typing",
  "All of the above",
 ]
},

{
 "numb": 33,
 "question": "Which of the following statements are used in Exception Handling in Python?",
 "answer":"All of the above",
 "options": [
  "finally",
  "except",
  "try",
  "All of the above",
 ]
},

 {
  "numb": 34,
  "question": "which of the following concepts is not a part of Python?",
  "answer": "pointers",
  "options": [
   "pointers",
   "loops",
   "dynamic typing",
   "all of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 35,
  "question": "which of the following are used for exception handling in python?",
  "answer": "all of the above",
  "options": [
   "try",
   "except",
   "finally",
   "all of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 36,
  "question": "which of the following types of loops are not supported by python?",
  "answer": "do-while",
  "options": [
   "for",
   "while",
   "do-while",
   "none of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 37,
  "question": "which of the following functions converts date to coressponding time in python?",
  "answer": "strptime()",
  "options": [
   "strptime()",
   "strftime()",
   "both A and B",
   "none of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 38,
  "question": "As what datatypes are the *args stored, when passed into a function? ",
  "answer": "tuple",
  "options": [
   "list",
   "tuple",
   "dictionary",
   "none of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 39,
  "question": "which of the following is not a valid set operation in python?",
  "answer": "",
  "options": [
   "union",
   "intersection",
   "difference",
   "none of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 40,
  "question": "which of the following are valid escape sequences in pyhton?",
  "answer": "all of the above",
  "options": [
   "\n",
   "\t",
   "\\",
   "all of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 41,
  "question": "which of the following are some common RDBMS in use?",
  "answer": "all of the above",
  "options": [
   "oracle",
   "mySql",
   "heidiSql",
   "all of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 42,
  "question": "what command is used to create a new table in SQL?",
  "answer": "create table",
  "options": [
   "create table",
   "build table",
   "generate table",
   "none of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 43,
  "question": "which of the following are types of unicode character string types in SQL?",
  "answer": "a&b",
  "options": [
   "nchar",
   "ntext",
   "a&b",
   "none",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 44,
  "question": "what does BLOB in SQL stand for?",
  "answer": "Binary Large objects",
  "options": [
   "Binary Large Objects",
   "Big Large Objects",
   "Binary Language for Objects",
   "none of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 45,
  "question": "which of the following datatype is most appropriate for storing string of 255 charecters?",
  "answer": "tiny text",
  "options": [
   "text",
   "tiny text",
   "blob",
   "binary",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 46,
  "question": "what happens when no value is inserted in an ENUM list?",
  "answer": "blank inserted",
  "options": [
   "no change",
   "code crash",
   "blank inserted",
   "none of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 47,
  "question": "abbrevate DDL",
  "answer": "data definiton language",
  "options": [
   "data definition language",
   "data derivation language",
   "dynamic data language",
   "detailed data language",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 48,
  "question": "what are rows of relation known as?",
  "answer": "tuple",
  "options": [
   "degree",
   "entity",
   "tuple",
   "none of the above",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 49,
  "question": "which of the following allows you to identify a tuple",
  "answer": "super key",
  "options": [
   "schema",
   "attribute",
   "super key",
   "domain",
  ]
 },

 {
  "numb": 50,
  "question": "which of the following is not an SQL command?",
  "answer": "delete",
  "options": [
   "delete",
   "order by",
   "select",
   "where",
  ]
 },
{
	"numb":51 ,
	"question":"flask is a frame work used for?" ,
	"answer":"python" ,
	"options": [
		"java",
		"python",
		"javascript",
		"none of the above",
	]
},

{
	"numb":52 ,
	"question":"by default, flask server is ___?" ,
	"answer":"multi threaded" ,
	"options": [
		"user level thread",
		"single threaded",
		"multi threaded",
		"none of the above",
	]
},

{
	"numb":53 ,
	"question":"what is the framework used for writing command line applications?" ,
	"answer":"click" ,
	"options": [
		"markupsafe",
		"jinja",
		"click",
		"none of the above",
	]
},

{
	"numb":54 ,
	"question":"flask is used for?" ,
	"answer":"web development" ,
	"options": [
		"web development",
		"mobile development",
		"database development",
		"cloud development",
	]
},

{
	"numb":55 ,
	"question":"which architecture does flask follow?" ,
	"answer":"MVC" ,
	"options": [
		"MVP",
		"MVC",
		"MVVM",
		"none of the above",
	]
},

{
	"numb":56 ,
	"question":"___ is a virtual python environment builder" ,
	"answer":"virtualenv" ,
	"options": [
		"venv",
		"env",
		"virtualenv",
		"none of the above",
	]
},

{
	"numb":57 ,
	"question":"what is the default port for flask?" ,
	"answer":"5000" ,
	"options": [
		"8000",
		"8080",
		"3000",
		"5000",
	]
},

{
	"numb":58 ,
	"question":"how to start a development server in flask?" ,
	"answer":"falsk run" ,
	"options": [
		"flask run",
		"run flask",
		"run",
		"flaskrun",
	]
},

{
	"numb":59 ,
	"question":"which method sends html form data to server?" ,
	"answer":"post" ,
	"options": [
		"get",
		"head",
		"post",
		"put",
	]
},

{
	"numb":60 ,
	"question":"CSS and JS are stored in which folder?" ,
	"answer":"static" ,
	"options": [
		"static",
		"component",
		"root",
		"config",
	]
},


]
